Culinary Example

1111 Karma Lane, Nashville, TN 37075 • (615) 537-1036 support@cpresumes.com

KITCHEN MANAGER | SOUS CHEF

Bringing 10 + Years of Professional Experience in Culinary Arts & Training as Follows:

- ♦ Menu Design
- Meal Preparation
- Special EventsCatering & Planning
- ♦ Inventory Control

- ♦ Kitchen Management
- ♦ Staff Management
- ♦ Project Management
- ◆ Customer Service
- ♦ Purchasing

- Business/Revenue Growth
- ♦ Team Building
- ♦ Training Analysis
- ♦ Cost Reduction

CORE COMPETENCIES

Recognized throughout career for being a visionary Chef and Corporate Trainer leveraging in-depth knowledge of the marketplace and the competitor landscape to significantly increase revenue and operational efficiency. Solid organizational, communication, and team building skills. Adept at conveying complex menu concepts in a simple and compelling manner. Expertise in Culinary Art trends, such as food preparation, menu development, event planning/catering, and inventory purchasing/control.

- ⇒ Results-driven with extensive Corporate Training experience and solid expertise in the areas of restaurant management, hospitality, cooking, and conflict management.
- ⇒ Highly skilled in creating eye appealing menus, maintaining high levels of sanitation and cleanliness, and resolving various issues in a timely manner.
- ⇒ Proven ability to effectively handle multi-task levels of responsibility with minimal direction from superiors while supervising personnel, providing team leadership, motivation, and development.
- ⇒ Demonstrates knowledge and experience in a diverse range of cuisines.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Love the Kitchen Cooking School

Kitchen Assistant

Assisted Owner with setup and preparation of food and materials for classroom presentations while involved in all aspects of instruction and demonstration of meals, as well as ensuring food safety, sanitation, and cleanup.

Ongoing, Various Clienteles

Personal Chef

Provides catering at dinner parties and special functions for a diverse clientele while teaching private cooking classes custom designed to suit client requirements. Develops menus in coherence with client dietary needs.

St. Maria Restaurant

Oct. 2004 - May 2006

Apr. 2008 - Present

May 2006 - Present

Private Chef

Planned and executed daily meals for parish priest according to client requests and dietary needs, as well as catered to various events, including annual staff Christmas Party, penance dinners, and other group events.

Moses Pastries May 2001 - Mar. 2002

Pastry, Pantry Supervisor

Supervised pastry and pantry staff and substitute Grill Cook. Gained extensive experience with production/preparation of food for all stations of service, banquets, and offsite special events. Assisted Chef with inventory control, purchasing, menu development, and recipe testing.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

(Continued)

Silver & Gold Golf Club

Dec. 2000 - May 2001

Cook

Prepared for breakfast and lunch daily while performing pantry cooking, grill cooking, special events catering, menu coasting, purchasing of inventory, and receiving.

Starbucks Jul. 2000 – Dec. 2000

Barista

Held accountable for various aspects of service, including front registers, expediting, espresso bar, and stocking supplies/inventory.

Health Systems PMT Nov. 1994 – May 2000

Corporate Training Specialist | Client Services Trainer | CSR, Client Specialist

Held numerous roles in the delivery of corporate training material, conducting of training needs analysis for various departments, training of all new client services reps, and resolution of client issues.

CERTIFICATIONS | TRAINING

Hospitality Supervision Certificate | Instructional Design Course & Training Needs Analysis Course Creative Training Techniques Course | Leading Effective Meetings & Handling Conflicts Performance Consulting Workshop | Communication Skills Workshop | Affirming Cultural Diversity How to Supervise | MS Office Training (PowerPoint, Word, Access, Project, Excel)

EDUCATION

Scottsdale Culinary Institute
Associate of Occupational Studies, 2001
Major: Le Cordon Bleu Culinary Arts
Honors Graduate, Le Cordon Bleu Diploma Awarded

Arizona State University **B.S., Justice Studies,** 1993 Major: Justice Studies







America's #1 Online Resume Builder

With Cover Letters

- Easy-to-use, guides you through step-by-step
- Resume templates, writing samples and tips
- One-click designs for the professional look you want
- Start from scratch or upload your resume



Already have an account?











Phone and Chat Hours: 7 Days a Week 6am to midnight EST



Write a resume - in minutes

Your resume is often your first and only chance to make a great impression on an employer. Managers will scan your resume for just 10 seconds to see if you're right for the job.

That's why your resume needs to be attractive and stand out. It needs to be well-written and highlight your skills to your best advantage.

The problem is most people don't know how to write a great resume and don't have the design skills to make it look professional.

- Our Resume Builder is designed to make resume-writing fast and easy.
- We match you with the right template and, in just one click, you can choose a professional design that will help you win the job.
- Our unique Text Tuner™ allows you to choose from hundreds of expert-written examples - no more writer's block!

Get the "most impressive resume builder on the market today". There's no risk; no obligation. We're so confident that you'll love our resume builder that you can try it for FREE.

According to our partners..."the most impressive resume builder on the market today."

onTargetiobs

YAHOO! hotjobs EmploymentGuide.com

Ret-Temps Joined

Customer Reviews

Job.com

"I was completely unaware of what companies are looking for in a resume. This product helped me word and format my professional resume and the examples were extremely useful. Overall, this is a great product. I would highly recommend these services." - A. Danihels

"This resume tool is so much better than templates - just upload or enter your resume content and you get your choice of designs. It's magical! Anyone can benefit from this tool: from students to executives!" - Belinda Yanda

View more reviews >



